Change streams is a
recent functionality
that we've added to MongoDB 3.6.
It allows developers
to integrate and build
applications that
rely on notifications
and can get the
stream-of-data changes that
happen in the database.
There's several
different use cases
that we can implement using
change streams, notification
engines, data migration
and synchronization,
continuous data
integration tools,
and filtered replication.
All good stuff.
In this lesson, we are
going to be looking
through the list of improvements
added in 4.0 that make change
streams even more fantastic.
First, we start with
one of my favorites,
opening a change stream
to listen to changes
on the database level.
So if I go into this
database of mine, M040,
and list for the collections,
I will have a bunch
of different collections.
Well, not bunch.
A few.
If I would like to see
all inserts happening
to any of the
existing collections,
I could open up a change stream
to the individual collection,
which requires me to know the
collection names ahead of time,
and obviously the database name,
which is fine for most cases
because the databases generally
know which namespaces,
databases, and collections
we want to watch
or want to interact with.
And open a change stream to
each one of those collections.
Now again, this is
pretty straightforward
once I know the exact
names of collections
that I want to listen to.
But let's say that I have a very
dynamic system where I really
don't know the exact
collection that is setting up.
What I do have is some
sort of database door
constant incremental collection
that will vary constantly
throughout either the execution
of a single application
or due to the fact
that that's the logic
that the database implements.
I could [INAUDIBLE] I could
list all collection names,
and append some sort
of watch command,
and this becomes
very, very tricky.
Or on the other hand,
it would be awesome
if I can just open
a change stream that
will listen to any
change happening
on any namespace
within that database.
And that's exactly what
MongoDB 4.0 allows.
We can just run the
DB.watch command
and we'll get a constant
stream of changes
happening regardless
of the collection they
are happening against.
That's pretty cool.
What if we extrapolate
that behavior
over a single set of collections
that might change constantly
over time to multiple
different databases?
Not only we have dynamic
creation of collections
but it's also dynamic creation
of databases themselves.
That's what we can also do
with MongoDB 4.0, which have
a cluster-level change stream.
And to do that what we would
need to do from the shell
is just use Mongo
or getMongo.watch.
This one will allow us to get
a full cluster view of changes
that are happening cluster-wide
regardless of the database
and regardless of the
collections that are being
changed at each point in time.
Again, don't use the shell
example too much because,
to exemplify its change
stream, the shell
is a poor man's alternative.
For a full experience,
you need to use a driver
in your preferred language.
However, the shell does
come with those necessary
helps to do the job.
Note that to enable change
streams across the cluster,
the change stream needs to
be opened against admin.
Now to collect all
collections changes that
are happening on
a single database,
the command needs to run
with aggregate equals 1.
And to get the full
view of changes
for a cluster, that requires
that the change stream
attributes will need to
be set with an option
allChangesForCluster
equals true.
Last but not the least, we've
added a new change stream
comment argument called
startAtOperationTime.
StartAtOperationTime will take
a valid cluster time value
and needs to be set on
every changeStream command.
No worries.
The 4.0 drivers provide
this by default.
You do not need to
find a valid cluster
time to set in your command.
But this allows a cluster
to start notifying changes
immediately after the
provided cluster time
without requiring the server
that is serving the change
stream to get its first change
to basically return back
in your results.
Let's look into
this simple diagram.
My application
opens up against A,
the database, a
change stream with
a particular
startAtOperationTime
equals t10.
In my oplog, if t10 is
available, or any document
that has been
applied in the oplog
after t10 and t10
inclusive, will
be returned regardless if the
change stream was open at t14.
Any cluster time will
be accepted as long
it is not older than the
oldest entry in your oplog.
So if instead of t10,
we would be using t8.
Since that would
not be in our oplog,
that could not be returned.
Finally, I just
want to highlight
that changeStream event messages
now return in operations
originated by a transaction two
new fields, transaction number
and logical session ID.
The transaction number
is a top-level field
that is equal to the
top-level oplog entry.
This [INAUDIBLE] refers to
the number of transactions
that happen within a session.
And the logical session
ID corresponds again
to the logical
session ID that is
present in the oplog that
affects the change reported
by the change stream.
To recap really
quickly, we can now
open change streams
to listen to cluster
and database-level changes.
We can also specify a
startAtOperationTime,
which allow the
application to get events
prior to the point where the
change stream has been opened
and avoiding waiting
for the first event
to reach the server to
start notifying events back
to the client.
A small syntax changes in
the change event document
that allows us to track down
transaction information related
to the reported changes.