Creating long
running transactions
or attempting to modify
over 1,000 documents
in a single asset
transaction can
result in a lot of
WiredTiger cache pressure.
A snapshot must maintain state
for all subsequent writes
since the snapshot was created.
Transactions use
the same snapshot
throughout the duration
of the transaction.
So if you have a large write
volume and an old snapshot,
state cannot be cleaned up
until the snapshot is killed.
This happens automatically
when the transaction releases
their locks after a commit.
Or WiredTiger can proactively
evict snapshots and abort
transactions if under
enough cache pressure.
By default, MongoDB
will automatically
abort any multi-document
transaction
that runs for longer
than 60 seconds.
When the transaction
aborts, an exception
is returned to the driver,
and the transaction
is fully rolled back.
To address this
safeguard, the transaction
should be broken into smaller
parts that allow execution
within this
configured time limit.
There are no practical
limits on the number
of documents that can be
read within a transaction.
But as a best practice, no
more than 1,000 documents
should be modified
within the transaction.
For operations that need to
modify more than this limit,
developers should
break the transactions
into separate parts that
process documents in batches.
Developers should add
application logic that catch
and retry a
transaction that aborts
due to a temporary exception,
such as the transient network
error or an election.
With the retryable
writes foundation,
the MongoDB drivers
will automatically
retry the commit statement
of a transaction.
DDL operations, like create
index or drop collections,
block behind all active running
transactions on that namespace.
And if a DDL
operation is running
and a new transaction is
unable to obtain a lock,
the transaction will abort.