When modifying documents,
MongoDB transaction statements
either obtain the right lock or
abort the entire transaction.
For example, if Transaction
1 writes to Document 1
but has not yet committed,
when Transaction 2 tries
to write a Document
1, Transaction 2
will abort with
a write conflict.
This logic avoids
deadlocking scenarios that
require manual intervention.
All reads can still occur
when a write lock is taken,
and no read will see uncommitted
writes, apart from those reads
within the transaction
holding the write lock.
Once the transaction
is committed,
all the write
locks are released,
and other transactions can now
successfully obtain the lock.
If Transaction 1
writes to Document 1
and has committed, when
Transaction 2 tries
to write to Document
1, Transaction 2
can now successfully obtain
the write lock and continue on.
When a write lock is
taken on the document,
all rights not within
a transaction context,
like a normal write or a find,
will block behind the commit
an infinitely retry
with backoff logic.
Write conflict
exceptions can also
be found at the time
the transaction commits.
This can happen if writes happen
before the write lock was taken
but are not reflected in
the transaction snapshot.
Write conflicts are classified
as transient transaction
errors.
And when encountered,
the transaction
is completely safe to retry.