With the document
data model, MongoDB's
existing single document
atomicity guarantees
can meet the data integrity
needs of most applications.
In fact, we estimate 80%
to 90% of applications
don't need multi-document
transactions at all.
However, some developers
have been conditioned
by 40 years of
relational data modeling
to assume that multi-document
transactions are
a requirement for any database
irrespective of the data model
they are built upon.
Others are concerned that while
multi-document transactions
aren't needed by their
application today,
they might be in the future.
And for some workloads,
support for ACID transactions
across multiple documents
is a requirement.
There are use cases where
transactional ACID guarantees
need to span a set of operations
across multiple documents.
One example of this
is with applications
that deal with the
exchange of values
between different
parties and require
all-or-nothing execution.
MongoDB already serves
these use cases,
but the introduction of
multi-document transactions
makes it even easier.
Before the availability of
multi-document transactions,
you would need to
programmatically set
transactional controls
at the application tier.
These can add complexity
that slows down
the rate of application
development.
For MongoDB 4.0
onwards, the database
automatically handles
multi-document transactions
for you.
Adding transactions
does not make MongoDB
a relational database, though.
All best practices relating
to MongoDB data modeling
continue to apply when
using multi-document ACID
transactions, or other
relational type features,
such as fully expressive JOINS
via the $lookup aggregation
pipeline stage.
Where practical, all data
relating to an entity
should be stored in a single
rich document structure.
Just moving data structured for
relational tables into MongoDB
will not allow users
to take advantage
of MongoDB's natural,
fast, and flexible document
model or its distributed
systems architecture.