Now that we've welcomed you to
the course, let's talk shop.
Let's go through the
logistics necessary for
your successful M040 journey.
In this course, you'll
find a set of lectures.
In each lecture,
you'll find a quiz
to test your understanding
of the [? exposed ?] topic
or feature.
The quizzes are not graded.
We will not be accounting
for that in your final course
grade.
In each chapter, aside
from the lecture,
you will find labs and homework.
By the way, we use those
terms interchangeably.
These are graded and count
towards your final grade.
And finally, we
have the final exam,
where we are going to go
through a set of exercises,
exam-like questions, that will
count towards your final grade.
The specifics of
the grading policy
are described in this
video lecture notes.
To help you out throughout
the lecture videos and labs,
we will provide you handout
materials and lecture
notes that will
contain all commands
and environmental variables
used in the videos.
As part of those
handouts, we provide
a Vagrant virtual machine with
all the necessary requirements
and dependencies installed
so you can follow along
with the demonstrations
and lab exercises.
The virtual environment is
here for your convenience.
It helps us standardize
a learning environment
and allow you to have a clean
environment to play with.
We recommend you use
that for all labs.
However, that is not mandatory.
If you wish to install
all the material
in your own environment,
that's totally fine, as well.
But remember, there might be
some external dependencies
you will have to
have installed to be
able to follow through
the labs and the lectures.
At the end of this
course, you will
be able to download a completion
certificate so that you
can brag about it with
your friends and family,
which is great.
With all that said, buckle
up, and enjoy the course.