Hello, I'm Aly Cabral, a product
manager on the core server.
And welcome to the
transactions lessons.
With snapshot isolation and
all-or-nothing execution,
transactions extend MongoDB's
ACID data guarantees
to multiple statements
and multiple documents
across one or many collections.
They feel just like
the transactions
you're familiar with from
relational databases.
They're easy to add to any
application that needs them,
and they do not impact the
performance of workloads
that don't require them.
With multi-document
transactions,
it's easier than ever for you to
address a complete range of use
cases with MongoDB.
And MongoDB 4.0 transactions
work across replica sets.
And transactions
across sharded clusters
are scheduled for MongoDB 4.2.
Unlike legacy
relational databases,
document databases
are different.
Rather than break related
data apart and spread it
across multiple
parent-child tables,
documents can store
related data together
in a single, rich,
strongly-typed structure using
subdocuments and
arrays to collapse
those parent-child tables
into a single document.
Up until 4.0, MongoDB has
provided ACID guarantees
at the document level.
The guarantees
provided by MongoDB
ensure complete isolation
as the document is updated.
Any errors cause the
operation to roll
back so that clients receive
a consistent view of the data.
With this design,
application owners
get all the same data integrity
guarantees as those provided
by legacy relational databases.
These single document
guarantees are often
sufficient for
most applications.
However, MongoDB
4.0, with the support
of multi-document transactions,
makes it easier than ever
to develop anything
against MongoDB.
In this chapter, we'll get
a feel for the transaction
syntax, dive into the
use cases, and go over
production considerations.