Greetings, my name
is Grigori Melnik.
I'm the head of product
for server and tools,
including Compass, our
intuitive GUI from MongoDB.
Many of you are already
familiar with Compass.
But for those who
are not, I encourage
you to download it
right away, and see
how it can help you explore
and manipulate the data,
as well as to build powerful
queries, including Geo queries.
Seriously, pause right now,
go to MongoDB Download Center,
and grab the latest
version of Compass.
See the notes below for a
link to the Download Center.
Compass is packed
with useful features
to help you be even more
productive with MongoDB.
Through the schema
visualizer, you
can understand the
frequency, types, and ranges
of fields in your data set.
Compass also offers you a view
into key server performance
metrics so you can
easily understand
your most active collections.
With visual explained
plans, you can
investigate how
queries are running
and resolve performance issues.
You can also view and create
document validation rules
as well as perform a
rudimentary index management,
reviewing the types and
size of your indices,
their utilization, and being
able to add or remove indices
at the click of a button.
In the past six months, the team
has introduced several highly
anticipated features.
Here are the highlights.
First stop is the
aggregation pipeline builder.
The aggregation framework is
one of the most powerful MongoDB
tools at your disposal.
Built on the concept of
data process and pipelines,
like Unix or in PowerShell,
the aggregation framework
lets users funnel
their documents
through a multi-stage pipeline
that filters, transforms,
sorts, computes, aggregates
your data, and more.
The aggregation
framework enables
you to perform
extensive analytics
and statistical
analysis in real time
and generate pre-aggregated
reports for dashboard.
To help you be even more
successful with the aggregation
framework, we've decided to
build a user interface for it.
And that's what the aggregation
pipeline builder is.
With its intuitive drag and drop
experience and code skeletons,
there is no need to worry about
bracket matching, reordering
stages, or remembering
operator syntax.
And of course, you also
get auto completion
for aggregation operators,
query operators, and even
document field names.
If you're authoring
your pipeline,
you can easily
preview the results.
This, in combination with the
ability to rearrange and toggle
stages on and off, make it easy
to troubleshoot your pipeline.
When you are satisfied
with the results,
the constructed
pipeline can be copied
into the clipboard for easy
pasting into your code,
or simply saved in your
favorites list for reuse later.
Also, we have added an ability
to import and export data
to and from your collections
in JSON or CSV formats.
This has been one of the
most consistently requested
features, and we're very happy
to deliver it in this release.
You're welcome.
Additionally, we have
refactored the Connect
dialog, making it more robust
and supporting the SRV records.
There are two
additional highlights
that I should also mention.
The first is the new
expert to language function
we've included in Compass.
This provides the
ability to convert
your queries and
aggregation pipelines
into Compass, to
the code in drivers
language of your choice.
Initially JavaScript, Java,
Python, and C#, are supported.
But you can expect
us to roll out
other languages pretty soon.
The second is that we have also
introduced two new editions
of Compass, the Isolated edition
and the Read-only the edition.
The isolated edition targets
regulated industries.
It restricts network requests
to TLS-encrypted TCP connections
to the server chosen
on the Connect screen.
All other outbound
connections are not
permitted in this edition.
So it doesn't pull
any automatic updates,
it doesn't send any telemetry,
or crash report into MongoDB.
Map rendering in the schema
view is also unavailable.
And you won't be able
to take advantage
of the in-product
live support system.
The read-only the version
limits certain CRUD operations
within your organization.
Users are limited strictly
to read operations.
All other functionality
remains pretty much the same
as in the standard
MongoDB Compass.
We thrive on your feedback.
Compass release cadence
is every two weeks.
And I'd like to encourage you to
send us your feedback, and not
only with issues and screams,
but also kudos and success
stories.
Also, don't forget
about the Plug-in
API we've exposed last year.
Build your extensions
and plugins for Compass
and share them with the
rest of the community.
Send us the links
to your plugins,
and we'll profile them on
the community plugin page.
And there you have it.
We're expanding the
capabilities of MongoDB Compass
to make you even
more productive.
Next in this module,
you will learn
how Compass is evolving from
the data exploration tool
to more IDE-like authoring tool.
You'll learn how
it can assist you
in building and troubleshooting
powerful aggregations.
Happy aggregating.
Happy coding.