By design, MongoDB's
transactions aggressively
abort to avoid
deadlocking scenarios that
require manual intervention.
It's important that all
applications against MongoDB
have the appropriate
retry logic that
listens for the transient
transaction error label that
exists for all errors
where it's safe to retry
the entire transaction
from the beginning.
Take a look at this example
where we catch exceptions
on any statement
within the transaction.
The label transient
transaction error
covers errors like network
failures or conflicts.
These are error classes that,
if a transaction is to rerun,
could result in a
successful commit.
Whereas parsing errors or
transactions that are too large
will not have this
label as re-running
could not lead to a
successful commit.
While every statement
can throw an exception
within a transaction,
errors on commit
should be handled specially.
Take a look at our
next example here.
The commit
transaction command is
considered a retriable right.
The driver will automatically
retry the commit transaction
once, after a retriable error.
Although this adds a
layer of protection,
the drivers retry attempt
of commit transaction
may, again, fail with
a retriable error.
In that case, both the
driver and the application
do not know the state
of the transaction.
Here, we are listening for
unknown transaction commit
results.
In our catch block,
where we can continue
to commit if necessary until
we know the transaction's
definitive status.
Or we can't implement
backoff logic here.
If we continue to send
commit, once there
is a reachable
primary, we will get
a definitive commit transaction,
or aborted transaction message.
Now, let's look at an example
putting it all together.
This retry logic should be
in all applications using
transactions, regardless
of whether you're
building against MongoDB
or relational systems.
Any transactional system could
raise an error on commit,
for example, from a network
blip leaving the transaction
in an unknown state.
And applications
should be prepared
to handle these errors.
At MongoDB, we want you to build
highly available applications
in line with best practices.