The slow operation log produced
by each individual MongoD
is a great resource
for debugging purposes
Each operation that surpasses
the defined slow ops
threshold by 100
milliseconds gets
logged in the
MongoD log file that
responded to such commands.
However, analyzing a lot of
log files in a distributed
environments, like a sharded
cluster might be challenging.
To address this
issue, in MongoDB 4.0,
logging slow operations is not
possible in the mongos as well.
A log message in MongoDB
has the following anatomy.
It has a time stamp, the
severity code, the component,
some contextual information,
and the message we want to log.
The structure of these log
messages is identical both
on mongos log
files and MongoD's.
As of 4.0, slow
queries will also
be logged not just system in
mongos process execution log
messages.
All update operations,
inserts, deletes
will be logged, expressing the
number of documents affected
in each write commands, the
number of shards affected,
and the time it
took to complete it.
All of that information
will be available to us
through the logs in our mongos.
Find commands and related
get more cursor iteration
operations will also be logged
if they surpass the slow MS
thresholds.
The number of return
documents, execution time,
the originating commands,
and the actual command
executed, as well as
the number of shards
being implicated on the
actual logged operation
will all be available.
For extended operation
control of slow operations
across the shards
with 4.0, we've
also added the capability
of killing operations
across shards that
are taking way
too much time from the mongos.
The ability to kill
cursors in sessions
initiated in a shard cluster.
Let's assume that we've
seen from our mongos
logs that there is a particular
query taking way much more time
to complete than we
originally anticipated just
on some get more command logs.
Using the current op or even
the dollar current op admin
database aggregation
command, we can track down
the infringing
operation information,
like the op ID related
with the offending query.
As a side note, the
current op command
also allows us to filter
the results of this command
to look for just local
operations in mongos.
It's really nice for
extending debugging.
Once we know the
slow operations ID,
we can emit a kill
operation in the mongos.
Then the mongos will stop
iterating over the open cursor
to every single shard
involved in the query
and send the kill operation
to the individual shards.
The operation itself
might take a bit longer
to be effectively
killed depending
on the execution
across the shards.
But that command will stop
reporting back results
to the client and will
get effectively removed
from the server.
The shard mechanism
will also ensure
that commands that die
in one single shard
get to die on the other
shards themselves.
So shard three died
for whatever reason.
The mongos will
kill the operations
on the remaining shards
so they don't keep
on running without purpose.
To recap, these two
new features of 4.0
allow for a better
traceability and debuggability
over the cluster
through the mongos logs.
And provide an extended
kill operational control
over long running operations
by allowing to kill operations
across shards, either by the
explicit command of killing
operations from the mongos
or by the mongos itself
detecting that a given operation
died in an individual shard
and killing all remaining
affected shard operations
related with that operation.
All good stuff of MongoDB 4.0.